[{"id":1, "Question":"What's in the Holy Bible (kjv)? ", "Answer":"The Old Testament and the New Testament"},
 {"id":2, "Question":"Who wrote the New Testament? ", "Answer":"The Holy Bible was written by about 40  men in a period of about 1600 years dating from 1500 BC to approx. 100AD."},
 {"id":3, "Question":"Did any of the authors of the New Testament walk with Jesus?", "Answer":"Matthew: (First Person) A tax collector and chosen by Jesus and walked with Jesus. Authored Matthew."},
 {"id":4, "Question":"", "Answer":"Mark: Author of the Gospel bearing his name. Mark was the Latin surname given to this young man whose Jewish name was John.  John Mark was causing to Barnabas, a prominent figure in the early church. Mark traveled with his cousin Barnabas in ministry, and later in years ministered to the Apostles Peter and Paul. "},
 {"id":5, "Question":"", "Answer":"Luke: (Second person) A Physician and a worker of Paul and traveled with Paul during his missionary Journeys. "},
 {"id":6, "Question":"", "Answer":"John: (First Person) One of the twelve Apostles, John was a fisherman and brother to one of the other twelve apostles James. The Apostle John is the author of the fourth gospel, three epistles and the Revelation. John was a close personal associate of Jesus being referred to as the \"...disciple whom Jesus loved.\""},
 {"id":7, "Question":"", "Answer":"Peter: Peter was one of the most prominent of the twelve Apostles. He was also a fisherman and brother to another of the twelve whose name was Andres. Peter was also referred to at times as Simeon (Acts 15:14) along with Cephas and Simon (John 1:43). Peter was a part of Jesus inner circle of disciples and remains an important person throughout the early church history. Peter is credited with authoring the two Epistles which bear his name and as being the likely source for Mark's Gospel."},
 {"id":8, "Question":"", "Answer":"Paul: (Heard Jesus speak --Acts 22:6) The Apostle Paul, although not one of the original twelve Apostles, was chosen by Jesus to be an apostle and to go out to bring the Gospel to the non-Jewish people of his day. Paul was a Jew of respectable heritage and a ranking member of the strict Jewish sect of the Pharisees. Paul was also a Roman citizen by birth which he used to his advantage in times of persecution. His name before his conversion was Saul and he was well known because he fiercely persecuted the early Christians. After his miraculous conversion Paul went on to live one of the most fruitful lives of service for the kingdom of God."},
 {"id":9, "Question":"", "Answer":"James: The author of the epistle of James; this man was also a brother of Jesus (Galatians 1:19). James was not one of the twelve Apostles but was clearly a leader in the  early church in Jerusalem. An important council in Jerusalem chaired by James was responsible for deciding that it was no longer a requirement to keep the ceremonial aspects of the law of Moses. Acts 12:17; 15:13-19 Gal 2:9. Along with being a member of Jesus household James also had the privilege of seeing Jesus after He rose from the dead. I Cor 15:5-7."},
 {"id":10, "Question":"", "Answer":"Jude: The author of one epistle of only twenty-five verses Jude was also a brother of James and of Jesus Jude 1; Gal 1:19 His name in Greek would be Judas, however this is not the traitor of Jesus, but the defender of the faith who's epistle speaks out boldly against the apostasy of his day."},
 {"id":11, "Question":"What books are in the Holy Bible? ", "Answer":"OT---Genesis  Exodus Leviticus Numbers Deuteronomy Joshua  Judges Ruth Samuel  Samuel  1Kings  2Kings 1Chronicles 2Chronicles Ezra Nehemiah Esther Job Psalms Proverbs Ecclesiastes Song of Solomon Isaiah Jeremiah Lamentations Ezekiel Daniel Hosea Joel Amos Obadiah Jonah Micah Nahum  Habakkuk Zephaniah  Haggai Zechariah Malachi Genesis Exodus Leviticus Numbers Deuteronomy Joshua  Judges Ruth Samuel  Samuel  1Kings  2Kings 1Chronicles 2Chronicles Ezra Nehemiah Esther Job Psalms Proverbs Ecclesiastes Song of Solomon Isaiah Jeremiah Lamentations Ezekiel Daniel Hosea Joel Amos Obadiah Jonah Micah Nahum  Habakkuk Zephaniah  Haggai Zechariah Malachi "},
 {"id":12, "Question":"", "Answer":"NT---Matthew Mark Luke John Acts Romans 1Corinthians 2Corinthians Galatians Ephesians Philippians Colossians First Thessalonians Second Thessalonians 1Timothy 2Timothy Titus Philemon Hebrews James 1Peter  2Peter 1John 2John 3John Jude Revelation "},
 {"id":13, "Question":"From what was the KJV translated from?", "Answer":"From the Textus Receptus:  The Textus Receptus is the text that has been used for 2,000 years by Christians. This is also the text that agrees with more than 95% of the Bible Manuscripts in Koine (common) Greek.  It is known by other names, such as the Traditional Text, Majority Text, Byzantine Text, or Syrian Text."},
 {"id":14, "Question":"Why the Textus Receptus?", "Answer":"In his essay Textual Criticism, Dr. Thomas Cassidy writes: \"The Traditional text of the New Testament has existed from the time of Christ right down to the present. It has had many different names down through the years"},
 {"id":15, "Question":"", "Answer":"Textus Receptus agrees with the vast majority of the 86,000+ citations from scripture by the early church fathers."},
 {"id":16, "Question":"", "Answer":"Textus Receptus is untainted with Egyptian philosophy and unbelief."},
 {"id":17, "Question":"", "Answer":"Textus Receptus strongly upholds the fundamental doctrines of the Christian faith: the creation account in Genesis, the divinity of Jesus Christ, the virgin birth, the Saviorâ€™s miracles, his bodily resurrection, his literal return and the cleansing power of his blood!"},
 {"id":18, "Question":"Why did early churches of the 2nd, 3rd centuries and all the Protestant Reformers of the\u00c2\u00a015th, 16th and 17th centuries choose Textus Receptus in preference to the Minority Texts?", "Answer":"Because of the following: 1. Textus Receptus is based on the vast majority (over 95%) of the 5,300+ Greek manuscripts in existence. That is why it is also called the Majority Text. 2. Textus Receptus is not mutilated with deletions, additions, and amendments, as is the Minority Text.  (Again, verifiable through Greek text) 3. Textus Receptus is only a coined named for the Greek Text originating in Antioch. Textus Receptus agrees with the earliest versions of the Bible: Peshitta (AD150) Old Latin Vulgate (AD157),  the Italic Bible (AD157) etc. These Bibles were produced some ****200 years before**** the Minority Texts (like Vatican and Sinai) favored by the Roman Catholic Church."},
 {"id":19, "Question":"What is the middle book of the Old Testament?", "Answer":"Proverbs"},
 {"id":20, "Question":"What is the middle chapter of the Old Testament?", "Answer":"Job 29"},
 {"id":21, "Question":"What is the middle verse of the Old Testament?", "Answer":"2 Chronicles 20:13 And all Judah stood before the Lord, with their little ones, their wives, and their children."},
 {"id":22, "Question":"What is the middle book of the New Testament?", "Answer":"2Thessalonians"},
 {"id":23, "Question":"What is the middle chapter in the New Testament?", "Answer":"Romans 131/2"},
 {"id":24, "Question":"What is the middle verse in the New Testament?", "Answer":"Acts 17:17"},
 {"id":25, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The longest verse in the Bible contains 90 words"},
 {"id":26, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The shortest verse is: John 11:35 \"Jesus wept\""},
 {"id":27, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"In the entire Bible there are:  773,692 words"},
 {"id":28, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"In the Old Testament there are:  592,439 words"},
 {"id":29, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"In the New Testament there are: 181,253 words"},
 {"id":30, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The Holy Bible is the most influential and most popular book in history"},
 {"id":31, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The Bible can be read aloud in 70 hours"},
 {"id":32, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"According to statistics from Wycliffe International, the Society of Gideons, and the International Bible Society, the number of new Bibles that are sold, given away, or otherwise distributed in the United States is about 168,000 per day."},
 {"id":33, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Number of books in the Bible: 66  (39  old testament, 27 new testament)"},
 {"id":34, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The system of chapters was introduced in A.D. 1238 by Cardinal Hugo de S. Caro"},
 {"id":35, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"There are 1,189 Chapters (929 old testament, 260 new testament)"},
 {"id":36, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The original manuscripts did not contain the chapter and verse divisions in the numbered form familiar to modern readers."},
 {"id":37, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The system of using verses was introduced in 1551 by Robertus Stephanus"},
 {"id":38, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Verses: 31,102 (23,145 old testament, 7,957 new testament)"},
 {"id":39, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Words: 783,137 (602,585 old testament, 180,552 new testament)"},
 {"id":40, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Letters: 3,116,480 (2,278,100  old testament, 838,380 new testament)"},
 {"id":41, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Number of promises given in the Bible: 1,260"},
 {"id":42, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Commands: 6,468"},
 {"id":43, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Predictions: over 8,000"},
 {"id":44, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Fulfilled prophecy: 3,268 verses"},
 {"id":45, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Unfulfilled prophecy: 3,140"},
 {"id":46, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Number of questions: 3,294"},
 {"id":47, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Longest name: Mahershalalhashbaz (Isaiah 8:1) & Jonathelemrechokim (Psalms 56:1-13)"},
 {"id":48, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Longest verse: Esther 8:9 (78 words) (Revelation 20:4)"},
 {"id":49, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Shortest verse: John 11:35 (2 words: \u201cYahushua wept\u201d).  This is the King James Bible.  Some Bibles might be Job 3:2 (Job said.) but King James has that as \u201cJob answered\u201d which is longer than Jesus wept. (John 11:35 is the shortest verse in the new testament)"},
 {"id":50, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Shortest chapter (by number of words): Psalm 117 (by number of words)"},
 {"id":51, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Longest book: Psalms (150 chapters) (Luke \u2013 new testament)"},
 {"id":52, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Shortest book (by number of words): 3 John (Obadiah \u2013 old testament)"},
 {"id":53, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Longest chapter: Psalm 119 (176 verses) (Luke 1- new testament)"},
 {"id":54, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Number of times the word \u201cGod\u201d appears: 4,094"},
 {"id":55, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Number of times the word \u201cLord\u201d appears: 6,781"},
 {"id":56, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Number of different authors: 40"},
 {"id":57, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The Author with the Most Books:  Moses is credited with writing the first 5 books in the Old Testament, & Paul wrote a total of 14 books in the New Testament"},
 {"id":58, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Number of languages the Bible has been translated into: over 1,200"},
 {"id":59, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"There are about 2.5 Billion to 6 Billion copies sold"},
 {"id":60, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Thomas Cranmer (1489-1556), Archbishop of Canterbury, reportedly memorized the entire Bible! Some historians record that it took him only three months to accomplish this amazing feat!"},
 {"id":61, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The most frequently cited old testament verse in the new testament is Psalm 110:1 YHWH said unto my master, Sit thou at my right hand, until I make thine enemies thy footstool. \u2013 quoted 18 times Matt. 22:44, 26:64, Mark 12:36, 14:62, 16:19, Luke 20:42-43, 22:69, Acts 2:34-35, Rom. 8:34, 1 Cor. 15:25, Eph. 1:20, Col. 3:1, Heb.1:3, 13, 8:1, 10:12-13, 12:2"},
 {"id":62, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The most mentioned man in the bible is David, mentioned 1118 times"},
 {"id":63, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The book of Isaiah is the oldest testament book referred to in the New Testament."},
 {"id":64, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The first human is recorded to be Adam in Genesis 2:7"},
 {"id":65, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The oldest man is recorded to be Methuselah, son of Enoch, who lived to be 969 in Genesis 5:27"},
 {"id":66, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Man was spoken to by a donkey,  in Numbers 22:28-30."},
 {"id":67, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Goliath was recorded to be the tallest man with a bed measuring 13\u00bd feet in length and 6 feet in width in Deuteronomy 3:11. (some say he was between 10-11ft)"},
 {"id":68, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":" Samson is recorded to be the strongest man in Judges 14:6 & Judges 15:5"},
 {"id":69, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The sun is recorded to have stood still for a whole day in Joshua 10:13."},
 {"id":70, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"There was an army with 700 left-handed men in Judges 20:16."},
 {"id":71, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Absalom\u2019s hair weighed about 6 pounds when it was cut annually, 2 Samuel 14:26."},
 {"id":72, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"A man who had 12 fingers and 12 toes, 2 Samuel 21:20."},
 {"id":73, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"King Solomon was the wisest person recorded that ever lived in 1 kings 3:12 & 10:24"},
 {"id":74, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"King Solomon was the richest man ever recorded in 1 Kings 10:14-29"},
 {"id":75, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"King Solomon had hundred wives and three hundred concubines in 1 Kings 11:3 (one can only assume he also had the most children because of this, but it is not recorded to my knowledge)"},
 {"id":76, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Eglon the Moabite King, who was killed by Ehud, is recorded to be the fattest person in Judge 3:17"},
 {"id":77, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Moses is recorded to be the meekest in Numbers 12:3"},
 {"id":78, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Nebuchadnezzar was the proudest man recorded in Daniel 4, whom YHWH humbled."},
 {"id":79, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"A day the sun went backward, Is Isaiah 38:8."},
 {"id":80, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"A prostitute who was an ancestor of Christ, Matthew 1:5"},
 {"id":81, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"There are 17 historical books, 5 poetic books & 17 prophetic books in the Old Testament."},
 {"id":82, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"There are 4 Gospels, 1 historical book, 22 letters & 1 apocalyptic book in the New Testament."},
 {"id":83, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Characteristics and traits of people were an important aspect of names in ancient Israel. For example, the name Nabal means \u201csenseless and fool\u201d, and Abigail indicated that this is what her husband amounted to (1 Sam 25:25)"},
 {"id":84, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The creation of a Sabbath Day created the first week, many nations call the 7th day of the week Sabbath to further prove this & also Genesis 2:1-3"},
 {"id":85, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The Bible revealed that the earth was round in 1000 B.C., 2500 years before \u201cman discovered it\u201d for himself in 1500 by sailing around the earth. Read Isaiah 40:22, & Proverbs 8:27"},
 {"id":86, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The Hydrological water cycle was revealed to many of the prophets before Roman engineer named Marcus Vitruvius discovered it. Read Ecclesiastes 1:6-7, Ecclesiastes 11:3, Job 26:8, Job 36:27-28, & Amos 9:6"},
 {"id":87, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"THE EARTH IS SUSPENDED IN NOTHING Job 26:7"},
 {"id":88, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The sea has valley\u2019s in the sea, was revealed to us in my books before Science \u201cdiscovered it\u201d, such as in Psalms 18:15, Jonah 2:6, 2 Samuel 22:16"},
 {"id":89, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The nations were afraid of the Sun, Moon & Stars because they did not understand them & even thought them to be Gods, but YHWH reveals to Jeremiah not to worry about them in Jeremiah 10:2"},
 {"id":90, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"There are paths in the sea which Matthew Maury in the 1800\u2019s discovered after reading Psalms 8:8.  He was an officer in the United States Navy, who believed his Bible & went out to prove this for himself. Maury wrote the first book on oceanography and became known as \u201cthe pathfinder of the seas\u201d\u2014 \u201cThe father of modern navigation.\u201d"},
 {"id":91, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The ways of the stars (Pleiades, Orion, and Arcturus) was revealed to Job in Job 38:31-32. Read more about this in this app.  Easy Bible Lookup."},
 {"id":92, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"YHWH prophesied about 150 years in advance who by name would conquer Babylon."},
 {"id":93, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The Old Testament prophetically mentions The Son of God 450+ years before the arrival of Jesus Christ."},
 {"id":94, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"Science says, TIME, SPACE and MATTER.   \"Genesis 1:1-In the beginning God created the heaven and the earth.\"\"  Beginning=Time  Heaven=Space  Earth=Matter "},
 {"id":95, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The Old Testament prophetically mentions The Son of God 450+ years before the arrival of Jesus Christ."},
 {"id":96, "Question":"Fact", "Answer":"The Holy Bible speaks of washing hands in running water to cleanse. In Leviticus 15:13 will prove this and this practice wasn't a common practice in the medical field until end of 19th century, 1870-1880."}]